The following content is provided under a Creative Commons license.
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to offer high-quality educational resources for free.
To make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw.mit.edu.
Okay, let's go. So, if you want to know the
subject of today's class, it's AX equal B.
I got started writing down different possibilities for AX equal B, and I got carried away.
It just appears all over the place, and for different sizes, different ranks, different situations, nearly singular,
nearly singular.
Not nearly singular.
And the question is, what do you do in each case?
So, can I outline my little two pages of notes here, and then pick on one or two of these topics to develop today,
and a little more on Friday about Graham-Schmidt?
So, I won't do much, if any, of Graham-Schmidt today, but I will do the others.
Okay. So, the problem is AX equal B.
That problem has come from somewhere.
We have to produce some kind of an answer, X.
Okay, so, I'm sort of going from good to bad, or easy to difficult in this list.
So, well, except for number zero, which is an answer in all cases, using the pseudo-inverse that I used.
I introduced last time.
So, that deals with zero eigenvalues and zero singular values by saying their inverse is also zero,
which is kind of wild.
So, we'll come back to the meaning of the pseudo-inverse, but now I want to get real here about different situations.
So, number one is the good, normal case when a person has a square matrix of,
really, reasonable size, reasonable
condition, the condition number O.
The condition number, I should
call it sigma one over sigma n.
It's the ratio of the largest to the smallest singular value,
and let's say that's within reason, not
more than a thousand or something. Then,
normal, ordinary elimination is going
to work, and Matlab, the command,
that would produce the answer is just
backslash. But, so this is the normal case.
Now, the cases that follow have problems of some kind.
And I guess I'm hoping that this is a sort of useful dictionary of what to do for you and me both.
OK. So, we have this case here
where we have too many equations.
So, it's a pretty normal case.
And it's the, we'll think mostly of solving by least squares, which leads us to the normal equation.
So, this is standard, happens all the time in statistics.
And I'm thinking in the reasonable case, so that would be x hat.
The solution A trans, this matrix
would be invertible. And reasonable size.
So, we could, actually, backslash would still solve that problem.
Backslash doesn't require a square matrix to give you an answer.
So, that's the good case where you would just, the matrix is not too big,
so it's not unreasonable
to form A transpose A. OK.
Now, here's the other extreme.
And like what's exciting for us is,
we have to put something more in to get a specific answer.
So, this is the underdetermined
case. I don't have enough equations.
So, I have to put something more in to get a specific answer.
And what makes it exciting for us is that that's typical of deep learning.
There are so many weights in a deep neural network that the weights would be the unknowns.
Of course, it wouldn't be
necessarily linear. It wouldn't be linear.
But it's a very simple problem.
And we have to find a solution.
And the problem is that we have many solutions, and we have to pick one.
Or we have to pick an algorithm, and then it'll find one.
And so, we could pick the minimum norm solution, the shortest solution.
That would be an L2
answer. Or we could go to L1.
But what we're trying to do in 2018 is, does deep learning and the iteration from stochastic
gradient descent that we'll see soon, pretty soon, does it go to the minimum L1?
Does it pick out an L1 solution?
That's really an exciting math question.
For a long time, it was sort of standard to say these deep learning, these linear equations,
these deep learning AI codes are
fantastic. But what are they doing?
We don't know the interior.
But when I say we, I don't mean I. Other people are getting there.
And I'm going to tell you as much as I can about it when we get there.
So those are pretty standard cases.
We're going to go to the next slide.
The second problem, we're going to go to the next slide.
They're things like columns. I'm
going to draw a picture of a column.
OK, so I'm going to draw a picture of a column.
And you can see that I've got two columns, n equals n, m greater than m, m less than n,
but not crazy. OK, now let me, the second
board will have more difficult problems.
or somehow you've got a matrix A whose columns are virtually
dependent, almost linearly dependent.
The inverse matrix is really big, but it exists.
Then that's when you go in and you fix
the columns. You orthogonalize columns.
Instead of accepting the columns A1, A2, up to AN
of the given matrix, you go in and you find
orthonormal vectors in that column space,
an orthonormal basis, q1 to qn. And
the two are connected by Gram-Schmidt.
And the famous matrix statement of Gram-Schmidt
is here are the columns of A, here are the columns of q,
and there's a triangular matrix that connects the two.
So that is a central topic, Gram-Schmidt,
in that idea of orthogonalizing.
It just appears everywhere. It appears
all over Course 6 in many, many situations
with different names. So I'm sort
of saving a little bit till next time.
And let me tell you why.
Because just the organization of Gram-Schmidt is interesting.
So Gram-Schmidt, you could do the
normal way. So that's what I teach in 1806.
Just take every column as it comes.
Subtract off projections onto the previous stuff.
Get it orthogonal to the previous
guys. Normalize it to be a unit vector.
Then you've got that column
go on. Shall I say that again?
And then I'll say it again two days from now.
So Gram-Schmidt, the idea is you take the columns.
You say the second orthogonal vector, q2,
will be some combination of columns
1 and 2, orthogonal to the first. Yeah.
Lots to do. And there's another order,
which is really the best way to do it.
It's called the B-type. It's the
better order to do Gram-Schmidt.
And it allows you to do column pivoting.
So this is my topic for next time,
to see Gram-Schmidt more
carefully. Right. OK. Yeah.
Column pivoting means you allow yourself to take the columns
might not come in a good order.
So you allow yourself to reorder them.
And we know that you have to do that for elimination, right?
And in elimination, it would be rows.
So elimination, we would have the matrix A. And we
take the first row as the first pivot row,
and then the second row, and then
the third row. But if the pivot is 2, 3.
So the pivot is 2, 3. Yeah. So the
pivot is 2, 3. Yeah. So the pivot is 2, 3.
Too small.
Then reorder the rows. So it's row
ordering that comes up in elimination.
And you, well, MATLAB just systematically says, OK,
that's the pivot that's coming up. The
third pivot comes up out of the third row.
But MATLAB says, look down that whole third
column for a better pivot, a bigger pivot.
Switch. Do a row exchange. So
there are lots of permutations then.
You end up with something there that permutes the rows.
And then that gets factored into LU.
So I'm saying something about elimination,
just a sort of side comment. That.
You would never do elimination without considering
the possibility of row exchanges. And then
this is Gram-Schmidt orthogonalization.
So this is the LU world.
Here's the QR world.
And here it happens to be columns
that you're permuting. So that's coming.
This is section 2.2
now. But there's more.
2.2 has quite a bit in it, including number 0,
the pseudo-inverse, and including some of these things.
Actually, this will be also in 2.2.
And maybe this is what I'm saying more about today.
So this would be, I'll put a little
star for today here. What do you do?
So this is a case where the matrix is
nearly singular. And you're in danger.
Its inverse is going to be big, unreasonably big.
And I wrote inverse problems there, because
inverse problems, that's a type of problem
that you need, application that you often need to solve,
or that engineering and science have to solve.
So I'll just say a little more
about that. But that's a typical.
That's a typical application in which you're near singular.
Your matrix isn't good enough to invert.
Well, of course, you could always
say, well, I'll just use a pseudo-inverse.
But numerically, that's like cheating.
You've got to get in there and do something about it.
So inverse problems would be examples.
Actually, as I write that, I think that would be a topic.
I should add that to the list of potential topics
for a three-week project, to look
up a book on inverse problems.
So what do I mean by an inverse
problem? I'll just finish this thought.
What's an inverse problem? Typically,
you know about a system, say a network, RLC
network. And you give it a voltage
or a current. You give it an input.
And you find the output. You find out
what current flows, what the voltages are.
But inverse problems are, suppose you
know the response to different voltages.
What was the network? You see
that, the problem? Let me say it again.
Discover what the network is from its
outputs. So that turns out to typically be
a problem that gives nearly singular
matrices. That's a difficult problem.
A lot of nearby networks would give virtually the same output.
So you have a matrix that's nearly singular.
It's got singular values very
close to 0. What do you do then?
Well, the world of inverse problems
thinks of adding a penalty term, some kind of a penalty term.
When I minimize this thing just by itself in the usual way,
A transpose A has a giant inverse.
The matrix A is badly conditioned.
It takes vectors almost to 0. 0. 0. So
that A transpose A has got a giant inverse.
And you're at risk of losing everything
to round off. So this is the solution.
You could call it a kind of cheap
solution. But everybody uses it.
So I won't put that word on videotape.
But that sort of resolves the problem.
But then the question, it shifts the problem.
Anyway, to what number, what should be the
penalty? How much should you penalize it?
You see, by adding that, you're going to make it invertible.
And if you make this bigger and bigger and bigger,
it's more and more well conditioned.
It resolves the trouble here. So this is
like, today I'm going to do more with that.
So I'll stop there and pick it up
after saying something about 6 and 7.
I hope this is helpful.
It was helpful to me, certainly, to see all these possibilities
and to write down sort of what the symptom is.
It's like a doctor, like a linear equation doctor.
Like you look for the symptoms, and then you propose some.
Something at CVS that works or doesn't
work. But you do something about it. OK.
So when the problem is too big, so up to now,
the problems have not been giant out of core.
But now when it's too big, well,
maybe it's still in core, but really big.
Then this is n 2.1. This is n 2.1. This
is n 2.1. This is n 2.1. This is n 2.1.
This is n 2.1. This is n 2.1. This
This is n 2.1. So that's to come back
to. The word I could have written in here
if I was just going to write one word
would be iteration. Iterative methods.
Meaning you take a step like, well,
conjugate gradient method is the hero of iterative methods.
And then that name I erased is Krylov.
And there are other names associated
with iterative methods.
So that's the section that we passed over just to get rolling,
but we'll come back to. So then that
one, you never get the exact answer,
but you get closer and closer. If
the iterative method is successful,
like conjugate gradients, you get pretty close pretty fast.
And then you say, OK, I'll take
it. And then finally, way too big.
Like nowhere, not in core, just your matrix,
you just have a giant, giant problem,
which of course is happening these days.
And then one way to do it is your matrix, I
mean, you can't even look at the matrix A,
much less A transpose A. A
transpose A would be unthinkable.
You couldn't do it in. In a year. So
randomized linear algebra has popped up.
And the idea there, which we'll see, is
to use probability to sample the matrix
and work with your samples. So
if the matrix is reasonably. It is not.
Is way too big, but not too crazy, so to speak.
Then you could sample the columns and
the rows and get an answer from the sample.
See, if I sample the columns of a matrix, I'm getting some.
So what does sampling
mean? Let me just complete this.
Say, add a little to this
thought. Sample a matrix.
So I have a giant matrix A. Might be sparse, of course.
I didn't distinguish over there sparse
things. That would be another thing.
So if I just take a random x, random x's, more than one,
but not the full n dimensions, those will
give me random guys in the column space.
So I have a giant matrix A. It might
be sparse, of course. But I'm not sure.
And if the matrix is kind of reasonable, those will give me.
It won't take too many to have a pretty reasonable idea
of what that column space is
like, and with its right hand side.
So this world of randomized linear
algebra has grown because it had to.
And of course, any statement can never
say for sure you're going to get the right answer.
But so using the inequalities of probability,
you can often say that the chance of being way off
is less than 1 and 2 to the 20th or something.
So the answer is, in reality, you get a good answer.
OK, that is like the end of this chapter
2.4. So this is all chapter 2, really.
The iterative methods in 2.1, most of this is in 2.2.
Big is 2.3, and then really big is
randomized in 2.4. OK, so now where are we?
You're going to let me know or not if this is useful to see.
But you sort of see what I'm doing.
I'm going to go back to the first one.
What are real life problems? And of course,
we're especially interested in getting
to the deep learning examples, which are underdetermined.
Then when you're underdetermined,
you've got many solutions.
And the question is, which one is a good
one? And in deep learning, I just can't
resist saying another word. You hope.
So there are many solutions. What to do?
Well, you pick some algorithm, like steepest descent,
which is going to find a solution.
So you hope it's a good one.
And what does a good one mean versus
a not good one? They're all solutions.
A good one means that when you apply it to the test data
that you haven't yet seen, it gives good results.
And the test data, you really, the solution
has learned something from the training
data, and it works on the test data.
So that's the big question in deep learning.
How does it happen that you, by doing gradient descent
or whatever algorithm, how does
that algorithm sort of bias the solution?
It's called implicit bias. How does that
algorithm bias the solution toward one? OK.
So you can think of a solution that's a
good generalizes, that works on test data.
And you could think of algorithms which
would give a approach to a solution that
did not work on test data. So that's
what you want to stay away from.
You want the ones that work. So
there's very deep math questions there,
which are kind of new. They
didn't arise until they did. And.
We'll try to say some of
what's being understood. OK.
Can I focus now on, for the rest, probably
the rest of today, on this case, when
the matrix is nearly singular.
So you could apply elimination, but it would give a poor result.
So the one solution is, well.
Yeah. One solution is the SVD.
I haven't even mentioned the SVD
here as an algorithm. But of course it is.
The SVD would give you an answer.
Boy, where should that have gone?
Well, space over here. The SVD.
So that produces, you have A equal u sigma
v transpose. And then A inverse is v sigma.
OK. OK. Sigma
inverse u transpose. OK.
So we're in the case here.
We're talking about number five.
Nearly singular, where sigma
has some very small singular values.
Then sigma inverse has some very big singular values.
So this is, you're really in kind of wild
territory here, with very big inverses.
So that would be one way to do it. But
this is a way to regularize the problem.
So let's just pay
attention to that. OK. OK.
OK. So suppose I minimize the sum of
Ax minus b squared and delta squared. OK.
And then I can multiply that by the
number of times the size of x squared.
And I'm going to use the L2 norm. It's
going to be least squares with penalty.
So of course, it's the L2 norm here too.
Yeah. OK. Suppose I solve that for a delta.
For some, I have to choose a delta, a positive delta.
Then I have a solvable problem. Even
if this goes to 0, or A does crazy things,
this is going to keep me away from singular.
In fact, what equation does that lead
to? So that's a least squares problem
with an extra penalty term. So it
would come, I suppose, let's see,
if I write the equation. OK. So
that means A delta i x equals b 0.
Maybe that is the least squares equation,
the usual normal equation for this augmented system.
Because what's the error here?
This is the new big A, A star, let's say.
A delta i x equals, this is the new b.
So if I apply least squares to that, what
do I do? I minimize the sum of squares.
And I, so least squares would minimize Ax minus b squared.
That would be from the first
components. And delta squared x squared.
So I can do this. I can do
this. I can do this. Let's see this.
This is the new b squared from the last component, which
is exactly what we said we were
doing. So in a way, this is the equation
that the penalty method is solving. And
the question is, so one question naturally
is, what should delta be? Well,
that question's beyond us today.
and how much noise is in the system
and everything. Yeah, the choice of delta.
What we could ask is the math
question, what happens as delta goes to 0?
So suppose I solve this problem.
Let's see, I could write it differently.
Shall I write the, what would be the equation here?
This part would give us the A transpose A.
And then this part would give us just the identity,
x equals A transpose B. I think, yeah, wouldn't that be?
So really, I've written here what
that is, is A star transpose A star.
This is least squares on this gives that
equation. So all of those are equivalent.
All of those would be equivalent. Stay.
Statements of what the penalized problem
is that you're solving.
And then the question is, as delta goes to 0, what happens?
Of course, when delta goes to 0, you're falling off the cliff.
Something quite different is suddenly going to happen there.
Maybe we could even understand
this question with a one by one matrix.
Yeah, I think this section starts with a
one by one. Suppose A is just a number.
Maybe I'll just put that on this
board here. Suppose A is just a number.
So what am I going to call
that number? Just one by one.
Let me call it sigma, because it's
certainly the leading singular value. OK.
So I'm going to write this down. OK.
So what's my equation that I'm solving?
A transpose A would be sigma
squared plus delta squared, one by one, x.
Should I give some subscript
here? I should, really, to do it right.
This is the solution for a given delta.
And I'm asking what happens.
So that solution will exist. Fine.
This matrix is certainly invertible.
That's positive semi-definite, at least.
That's positive semi-definite.
And what about delta squared i?
It is positive definite, of course,
just the identity with a factor.
So this is a positive definite
matrix. I certainly have a solution.
And let me keep going on this one by one case.
This would be A transpose A is just
a sigma. I think it's just sigma B. OK.
So this is A is one by one.
And there are two cases here.
Sigma bigger than 0 or sigma equals 0.
And in either case, I just want to know
what's the limit. So the answer x. Yeah.
Let me just take the right hand
side. Well, that's fine. Yeah. OK.
So am I computing OK? Using the
penalized thing on a one by one problem,
which you could say is kind of a little bit small for solving
this equation or equivalently minimizing
this. So here I'm finding the minimum of.
I'm going to write it out. Sigma squared x
squared of A was sigma x minus B squared
plus delta squared x squared. I
guess I'm hoping that if I found that.
You see, it's just one by one, just a number.
And I'm hoping that calculus will agree with linear algebra
here, that if I find the minimum
of this. So let me write it out.
So sigma squared x squared of A was sigma x minus B squared
plus delta squared x squared. And then
minus 2 sigma x B and then plus B squared.
And now I'm going to find the minimum,
which means I'd set the derivative to 0.
So I get 2 sigma squared and
2 delta squared. I get a 2 here.
And this gives me the x derivative.
It's 2 sigma B. So I get a 2 there.
And that's the equation.
So I can solve that equation.
x is sigma B, sigma over sigma squared plus delta squared B.
So it's really that quantity.
I want to let delta go to 0.
So again, what am I doing here?
I'm taking a one by one example just
to see what happens in the limit as
sigma, as delta, sorry, delta goes to 0.
What happens? So I
just have to look at that.
What is the limit of that thing in a circle as delta goes to 0?
So I'm finding out for a one by one problem
what a penalized least squares problem.
So I'm not going to go into the problem.
Ridge regression all over the place.
What happens? OK. So what happens
to that number as delta goes to 0?
1 over sigma. So now, let delta go to 0.
So that approaches 1 over sigma, right?
Because delta disappears. And sigma
over sigma squared. 1 over sigma.
And delta goes to 0. So delta goes to 1
over sigma squared. Now, that's much worse.
But what's the other possibility here?
The other possibility is that sigma is 0.
I didn't say whether this 1 by 1 matrix was invertible or not.
If sigma is not 0, then I go to 1 over sigma.
If sigma is really small, it'll take a while.
even compared to sigma until finally that term goes away
and I just have 1 over sigma. But
what if sigma is 0? Sorry to get excited.
About 0. Who would
get excited about 0?
OK, so this is the case when this
is 1 over sigma if sigma is positive.
And what does it approach if sigma is 0?
0. Because this is 0. The whole problem
was like disappeared here. The sigma was 0.
Here is a sigma. So anyway, if sigma
is 0, then I'm getting 0 all the time.
But I have a decent problem
because the delta squared is there.
I have a decent problem until the
last minute. My problem falls apart.
Delta goes to 0. And I have a 0
equals 0 problem. I'm lost. But.
The point is the penalty kept me positive,
kept me with this delta squared term
until the last critical moment. It
kept me positive even if that was 0.
If that is 0 and this is 0, I still have something here.
So I still have a problem to
solve. And what's the limit then?
So 1 over sigma if sigma is
positive. And what's the answer?
What's the answer if sigma is not positive?
It's 0. Just tell me. I'm getting 0.
I get 0 all the way.
And I get 0 in the limit.
And now let me just ask, what have I
got here? What is this sudden bifurcation?
What's the? Do I recognize this? The
inverse in the limit as delta goes to 0
is either 1 over sigma, if that makes sense,
or it's 0, which is not like 1 over
sigma. 1 over sigma, as sigma goes to 0,
this thing is getting bigger and
bigger. But at sigma equals 0, it's 0.
You see, that's a really strange kind of a limit.
And what word now it would be over there?
What have I found here in this limit?
You see, I say it again because it
was exactly right. The pseudoinverse.
So this system choose delta greater than 0,
then delta going to 0, the solution goes to the pseudoinverse.
That's the key fact.
When delta is really, really small,
then this behaves in a pretty crazy way.
If delta is really, really small,
then sigma is bigger, or it's 0.
If it's bigger, you go this
way. If it's 0, you go that way.
So that's the message then, that this penalized least squares
approaches as the penalty gets smaller and smaller,
approaches the correct answer, the always correct answer,
with that sudden split between
0 and not 0. Right? Right.
So that's the 0, 0 that we associate
with the pseudoinverse. Yeah.
Of course, in a practical case, you're
trying to find the resistances and inductances in a circuit
by trying the circuit and looking at the output B
and figuring out what input, what the
unknown x is and what the current is.
And the one that's the most important is the unknown system
parameters, the voltage and not the voltage and current,
but the resistance and inductance
and capacitance. OK. So that's now.
I've only proved that in the one by one case.
You may say that's not much of a proof.
In the one by one case, we could see it
happen in front of our eyes. So
really, the step I haven't taken here
is to complete that to any matrix
A. So that's the statement then.
That's the statement.
Yeah.
So that's the
statement. For any.
For any matrix A, this matrix A transpose A plus delta
squared inverse times A transpose, that's
the solution matrix to our problem, right?
Yeah. That's what I wrote down up there.
I take the inverse and pop it over there.
That approaches A
plus. This. Pseudoinverse.
And that's what we just checked for one by one.
For one by one, this was sigma
over sigma squared plus delta squared.
And it went to either to 1 over
sigma or to 0. It split in the limit.
It shows that limits can be delicate. Yeah.
You know, the limit as delta goes to 0,
this thing is suddenly discontinuous.
It's this number that's growing.
And then suddenly at 0, it falls back to
0. Anyway, that would be the statement.
Actually, statisticians discovered the pseudoinverse
independently of linear algebra history
of it, because statisticians did exactly.
That. To regularize the problem,
they introduced a penalty
and worked with this matrix. So
statisticians were the first to see that.
To think of that as a natural thing to
do in a practical case. Add a penalty. OK.
So I guess, so this is adding a penalty.
But remember that we stayed with L2 norms.
Staying with L2, least squares.
We could ask what happens. Yeah.
Suppose the penalty is the L1 norm.
Suppose I minimize. I'm not up to
do this today. Suppose I minimize. That.
Maybe I'll do L2. But I'll do
the penalty guy in the L1 norm.
I guess I'm not, yeah, I'm
certainly not an expert on that.
Or you could even think just that
power. So that would have a name.
That's a statistician. A statistician
invented this. It's called the L1.
It's a lasso in the L1 norm. And it's a
big deal. Statisticians like the L1 norm.
Because it really, because it gives sparse solutions.
It gives sort of more genuine solutions
without a whole lot of little
components in the answer. Yeah.
So this was an important
step. And so maybe. Maybe.
Let me just say again where we are in that big list.
The two important ones that I haven't done
yet are these iterative methods in 2.1.
So that's like conventional linear algebra,
just how to deal with a big matrix.
Maybe with some special structure.
That's what linear algebra is, numerical
linear algebra is all about. Yeah.
And then Gram-Schmidt with or without pivoting,
which is a workhorse of numerical computing.
And I think I better save that for next time.
So this is the one I picked for this
time. And we saw what happened in L2.
Well, we saw it for one by one. Would
you want to? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
So you can extend to prove this
for any A, going beyond one by one.
How would you prove such a thing
for any A? I guess I'm not going to do it.
It's too painful. But
how would you do it?
If you want to prove something about matrices,
about any matrix, the SVD is the best thing you could have,
the best tool you could have. I can write
this in terms of the SVD. I just plug in.
I just plug in A equals whatever the SVD tells me to put in
there, u sigma B transpose.
Plug it in there. Simplify it. Using.
The fact that these are orthogonal. You
know, I always, if I have any good luck,
it'll get an identity somewhere from
there and an identity somewhere from there.
And it'll all simplify.
It'll all diagonalize.
That's what the SVD really does, is
turns my messy problem into a problem about
the diagonal matrix sigma in the middle.
So I might as well put sigma in there.
Sigma in the middle. Yeah. Why not?
Before we give up on it, a special case of that,
but really the genuine case would be when A is sigma.
Sigma transpose sigma plus delta squared I inverse times sigma
transpose approaches the
pseudo inverse sigma plus. Yeah.
And the point is the matrix sigma here is diagonal.
And oh, I'm practically there, actually.
Why am I close to being able to read this
off? Well, everything is diagonal here.
Diagonal, diagonal, diagonal.
And what's happening on those diagonal entries?
Well, you have to take my word that when I plugged in the SVD,
the u and the v kind of got separated
out to the far left and the far right.
And it was that that stayed in the middle.
So it's really this is the heart of it.
And how do you suppose?
So that's a diagonal matrix.
So I'm just looking at what happens
on each. Yeah. Diagonal entry.
And which problem is that?
The question of what's happening on a typical diagonal entry
of this thing is what
question? The one by one case.
Now, one by one, because each entry in the
diagonal is not even noticing the others.
Yeah. So that's the logic, and it would be
in the. No. Triangular to which it is not.
What is that? OK. So I already have
those seven retreat time now connected.
And the last two experiences of moved
heraus is not Death, but Ret Shooting.
So I write up two ways of going around
these, both theanged and the Busanian.
Right? The main
message in today's lecture
is in this list of different types of problems that appear
and different ways to work with them.
And we haven't done Gram-Schmidt,
and we haven't done iteration.
So this chapter is a survey of, well,
more than a survey of what
numerical linear algebra is about.
And I haven't done random
yet. Sorry, that's coming too.
So three pieces are still to come,
but let's take the last two minutes off and call it a day.